kellydunn

General

I am a Professional Software Engineer with a decade of experience in various industries, including Education, Gaming, Music, IOT, Marketing, and Finance. I have held positions as an Engineer on Frontend, Backend, Infrastructure, Data, and Platform teams.

I have built Web Services, ETL pipelines, Media Streaming Services, Third-party Integrations, Open Source Libraries, and CI/CD pipelines. I have debugged and analyzed low-level performance problems, led 24/7 oncall rotations, and created policies that measurably increased reliability and reduced outages.

I have been a Lead Engineer for small engineering teams focusing on Site Reliability Engineering and Distributed Systems. I've provided training, tooling, and mentorship for all levels of engineering. I've also been an active participant in hiring, architectural design, and capacity planning.

Professional Experience

Splice

Technical Lead - Search March 2019 - Present

Improved p99 Search Latencies 100x to sub 100ms responses. Led and oversaw an initiative to migrate legacy search
infrastructure to a more modern and managed alterantive. Productionalized an experimental ML feature in ElasticSearch.

Senior Software Engineer October 2018 - March 2019

· Built and maintained backend web services.

Technologies: Go, MySQL, ElasticSearch, Docker, AWS, GCP, Terraform, SQS, Memcache, Redis

Simple

Lead Engineer - SRE / Platform Engineering July 2016 - August 2018

• Improved Mean Time to Recovery by 50%, and decreased the number of Outages per day by 60% in six months.

Senior Software Engineer July 2015 - July 2016

Built and maintained backend web services.

Technologies: Ruby, Go, Java, Scala, Kafka, PostgreSQL, SQS, DynamoDB, AWS, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes

Simply Measured

Software Engineer - Product / Data October 2013 - June 2015

- Created Map Reduce jobs that normalized billions of rows of Facebook and Youtube data.
- Identified and fixed memory leaks in mission critical worker processes.
- Created supporting web services that decoupled SimplyMeasured's web product from the Salesforce CRM.

Technologies: Ruby, Go, Java, RabbitMQ, MySQL, HBase, Memcache

Sifteo

Software Engineer December 2011 - July 2013

- · Created an online Game Marketplace, which serviced tens of thousands of Sifteo Game purchases and downloads.
- Created an Auditing Service, which collected Quality Assurance data on over 300,000 Sifteo Products created overseas.

Technologies: Ruby, Javascript, C++, C#, PostgreSQL, Redis

Professional and Freelance Software Contracting

Software Engineer May 2010-December 2011

- Built web services for clients as a Software Engineer at Originate
- Created web services that enabled musicians to distribute their music as a Software Engineer for Kelly Dunn LLC

Technologies: Ruby, Java, Javascript, C, C++

University of Washington

Teaching Assistant August 2008 - August 2010

• Taught fundamentals of Computer Science such as Data Structures, Algorithms, Databases, and Web Development.

Technologies: Java, Javascript, MySQL, Ruby

Education University of Washington

Bachelor of Arts in Japanese Linguistics September 2006 - June 2010